Ovarro Hanson

160B Attingham Drive, Dudley, DY1 3HY Phone (mobile): 07498167172 - <u>ovarrohanson18@yahoo.com</u>,

linkedin.com/in/ovarro-hanson, https://github.com/Ohanson18

Professional summary

I am a dedicated and versatile professional with ten years of expertise in combined management and customer service, along with a passion for AWS services. I have a proven record of reliability, problem-solving skills, and obtaining results to meet the requirements of local customers and international business partners. Recently I completed 12 weeks of intense remote training with Generation, on the AWS re/Start programme. During this time, I gained substantial knowledge of IT fundamental skills in Python, Linux Operating system, Databases, Networking, Security and AWS Cloud Computing. I am keen to put this training into action and further develop my skills, as I work towards my career goal of becoming a Cloud Solutions Architect.

Skill

- Linux
- Python
- Networking
- AWS-Cloud Computing concepts and core services
- Time management
- Customer service
- Critical thinking
- Administration and management

Experience

15/07/2020 09/2020

AWS re/Start program

Cloud Ops engineer (trainee)

- Covered the following: Linux (CLI), Networking, Security, Programming and Databases, Python, Cloud Computing concepts and core services.
- Labs that provided me hands-on experience using AWS services such as: using AWS Systems Manager, using Auto Scaling, troubleshooting VPC.

05/2013 to 11/2019

Property Manager

Bromfield's Property - Southfield, Saint Elizabeth, Jamaica

- Collect and deposit money into accounts, disburse funds from cash accounts to pay bills or invoices, keep records of collections and disbursements, and ensure that accounts are balanced.
- Meet with prospective tenants to show properties and explain terms of occupancy.
- Act as liaisons between tenants and owners ensuring effective communication.

- Investigate complaints, disturbances and violations and resolve problems following management rules and regulations.
- This role allowed me to build excellent communication and persuasive skills, along with improving my numerical reasoning.

03/2013 to 11/2019

General Manager

Young Dreamers Research Centre - Southfield, Saint Elizabeth, Jamaica

- Use computers for various applications, such as database management and word processing.
- Collect and deposit money into accounts, disburse funds from cash accounts to pay bills or invoices, keep records of collections and disbursements, and ensure that accounts are balanced.
- Operate office equipment, such as: copiers or phone systems, configuring router and arrange for repairs when equipment malfunctions.
- In this role I learned how to take personal responsibility, demonstrated teamwork and adopted growth mindset and persistence.

09/2018 to 10/2019

Private Hire Taxi

Self Employed - Southfield, Saint Elizabeth, Jamaica

- Follow safety regulations and laws governing vehicle operation, and ensure that passengers follow safety regulations.
- Arrange to pick up particular customers or groups on a regular schedule.
- This job allowed me to better develop my customer service and time management skills.

Education

03/2020 Generation UK and Ireland

AWS re/Start program

07/2009 Human Employment and Resource Training Trust/National Training Agency

Electrical Installation: level 2 -the equivalent to a BTEC Diploma

Interests

- Volunteering and community Involvement: National Youth Council of Jamaica, PRO for the parish of St. Elizabeth (2018-2019)
- Carpentry
- Nature walks
- Puzzles

Achievement

03/2020 Highfield level 2 award in the principles of fire safety (RQF)

09/2020 AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner certification